{
    "id": "d56d5d48-56e5-4d3d-b6b7-ec1a9d7314e6",
    "name": "Welding Safety",
    "topicId": "d56d5d48-56e5-4d3d-b6b7-ec1a9d7314e6",
    "questions": [
        {
            "id": "d56d5d48-56e5-4d3d-b6b7-ec1a9d7314e6",
            "topicId": "d56d5d48-56e5-4d3d-b6b7-ec1a9d7314e6",
            "question": "Who is responsible for the personal safety of everyone in the shop?",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "Shop foreman",
                "Plant superintendent",
                "Individual worker",
                "Alberta Occupational Health and Safety"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["Individual worker"],
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "d56d5d48-56e5-4d3d-b6b7-ec1a9d7314e6",
            "topicId": "d56d5d48-56e5-4d3d-b6b7-ec1a9d7314e6",
            "question": "What should you do immediately if you receive a major contact burn?",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "Rub the affected area with antibiotic cream",
                "Seek professional medical attention",
                "Cool the burned area by immersing in cool, still water",
                "Place the burned area under a fast-running warm water tap"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["Cool the burned area by immersing in cool, still water"],
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "d56d5d48-56e5-4d3d-b6b7-ec1a9d7314e6",
            "topicId": "d56d5d48-56e5-4d3d-b6b7-ec1a9d7314e6",
            "question": "Exposure to infrared light without proper eye protection can cause:",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "Sunburn",
                "Arc flash",
                "Retina damage",
                "Temporary blindness"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["Retina damage"],
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "d56d5d48-56e5-4d3d-b6b7-ec1a9d7314e6",
            "topicId": "d56d5d48-56e5-4d3d-b6b7-ec1a9d7314e6",
            "question": "Temporary blindness is caused by the eyes being exposed to high levels of:",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "Red light",
                "Yellow light",
                "Green light",
                "Visible light"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["Visible light"],
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "d56d5d48-56e5-4d3d-b6b7-ec1a9d7314e6",
            "topicId": "d56d5d48-56e5-4d3d-b6b7-ec1a9d7314e6",
            "question": "When would you use protective screens if you were performing an arc welding operation?",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "In a high wind velocity situation",
                "If you were near combustibles",
                "If you were in an explosive atmosphere",
                "If there were other workers nearby"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["If there were other workers nearby"],
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "d56d5d48-56e5-4d3d-b6b7-ec1a9d7314e6",
            "topicId": "d56d5d48-56e5-4d3d-b6b7-ec1a9d7314e6",
            "question": "All the following are symptoms of hypothermia except:",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "Dehydration",
                "Uncontrollable shivering",
                "Dizziness",
                "Light-headedness"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["Dehydration"],
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "d56d5d48-56e5-4d3d-b6b7-ec1a9d7314e6",
            "topicId": "d56d5d48-56e5-4d3d-b6b7-ec1a9d7314e6",
            "question": "Permanent eye damage in the form of cataracts may result from over exposure to which harmful light ray?",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "Visible",
                "Infrared",
                "Ultraviolet",
                "Reflected"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["Infrared"],
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "d56d5d48-56e5-4d3d-b6b7-ec1a9d7314e6",
            "topicId": "d56d5d48-56e5-4d3d-b6b7-ec1a9d7314e6",
            "question": "When cutting or welding on metals plated with cadmium:",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "There are no significant health hazards present",
                "Appropriate respiratory protective equipment should be used",
                "General ventilation is adequate",
                "A dust filter mask should be worn"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["Appropriate respiratory protective equipment should be used"],
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "d56d5d48-56e5-4d3d-b6b7-ec1a9d7314e6",
            "topicId": "d56d5d48-56e5-4d3d-b6b7-ec1a9d7314e6",
            "question": "When oxygen reacts with ultraviolet light from welding, the gas produced is:",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "Phosphine",
                "Nitrogen dioxide",
                "Ozone",
                "Carbon monoxide"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["Ozone"],
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "d56d5d48-56e5-4d3d-b6b7-ec1a9d7314e6",
            "topicId": "d56d5d48-56e5-4d3d-b6b7-ec1a9d7314e6",
            "question": "To determine the effectiveness of a shop's general mechanical ventilation system, all visible smoke and fumes should be cleared within:",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "5 seconds",
                "30 seconds",
                "5 minutes",
                "1 hour"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["30 seconds"],
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "d56d5d48-56e5-4d3d-b6b7-ec1a9d7314e6",
            "topicId": "d56d5d48-56e5-4d3d-b6b7-ec1a9d7314e6",
            "question": "Which type of radiant energy can cause welding flash?",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "Visible light",
                "Infrared light",
                "Ultraviolet light",
                "Gamma rays"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["Ultraviolet light"],
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "d56d5d48-56e5-4d3d-b6b7-ec1a9d7314e6",
            "topicId": "d56d5d48-56e5-4d3d-b6b7-ec1a9d7314e6",
            "question": "Permanent eye damage in the form of cataracts or retina damage may result from over exposure to which harmful light ray?",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "Visible",
                "Infrared",
                "Ultraviolet",
                "Reflected"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["Infrared"],
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "d56d5d48-56e5-4d3d-b6b7-ec1a9d7314e6",
            "topicId": "d56d5d48-56e5-4d3d-b6b7-ec1a9d7314e6",
            "question": "What type of gloves are recommended for oxyfuel cutting?",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "Hard twist cotton",
                "Silicon-treated nylon",
                "Dry-tanned leather gauntlet style",
                "Oil-treated cowhide"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["Dry-tanned leather gauntlet style"],
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "d56d5d48-56e5-4d3d-b6b7-ec1a9d7314e6",
            "topicId": "d56d5d48-56e5-4d3d-b6b7-ec1a9d7314e6",
            "question": "Which type of material offers the best protection against sparks and molten slag?",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "Leather",
                "Wool",
                "Nylon",
                "Cotton"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["Leather"],
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "d56d5d48-56e5-4d3d-b6b7-ec1a9d7314e6",
            "topicId": "d56d5d48-56e5-4d3d-b6b7-ec1a9d7314e6",
            "question": "Which metal, when heated or welded, can produce metal fume fever if the fumes are inhaled?",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "Aluminum",
                "Zinc",
                "Chromium",
                "Cobalt"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["Zinc"],
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "d56d5d48-56e5-4d3d-b6b7-ec1a9d7314e6",
            "topicId": "d56d5d48-56e5-4d3d-b6b7-ec1a9d7314e6",
            "question": "Fumes are:",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "Small, condensed particles of metal that have vaporized",
                "Substances having free form mixed with air",
                "Liquids that have been evaporated using heat",
                "Solid particles dispersed in the atmosphere"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["Small, condensed particles of metal that have vaporized"],
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "d56d5d48-56e5-4d3d-b6b7-ec1a9d7314e6",
            "topicId": "d56d5d48-56e5-4d3d-b6b7-ec1a9d7314e6",
            "question": "The first line of defence against welding fumes and gases is:",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "A supplied air respirator",
                "Source extraction equipment",
                "To complete all welding during the first half of your work shift",
                "To weld outside"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["To weld outside"],
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "d56d5d48-56e5-4d3d-b6b7-ec1a9d7314e6",
            "topicId": "d56d5d48-56e5-4d3d-b6b7-ec1a9d7314e6",
            "question": "OEL's are based on all the following except:",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "A normal eight hour working day",
                "A fifteen-minute short-term exposure",
                "A ceiling that must never be exceeded",
                "A worker's tolerance to fume inhalation"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["A worker's tolerance to fume inhalation"],
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "d56d5d48-56e5-4d3d-b6b7-ec1a9d7314e6",
            "topicId": "d56d5d48-56e5-4d3d-b6b7-ec1a9d7314e6",
            "question": "Welding with wet gloves increases the risk of:",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "Drowsiness",
                "Skin irritation",
                "Electrical shock",
                "Suffocation"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["Electrical shock"],
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "d56d5d48-56e5-4d3d-b6b7-ec1a9d7314e6",
            "topicId": "d56d5d48-56e5-4d3d-b6b7-ec1a9d7314e6",
            "question": "What device breaks the current flow while still at a low level to protect people from electrical shock?",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "Heavy duty circuit breaker (HDCB)",
                "Ground fault circuit interrupter (GFCI)",
                "Heavy duty electrode holder (HDEH)",
                "Transformer rectifier silicon diode (TRSD)"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["Ground fault circuit interrupter (GFCI)"],
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "d56d5d48-56e5-4d3d-b6b7-ec1a9d7314e6",
            "topicId": "d56d5d48-56e5-4d3d-b6b7-ec1a9d7314e6",
            "question": "Prior to cutting or welding, cover combustible floors with:",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "Metal or wet sand",
                "Flammable liquid",
                "Wood or plastic",
                "Tarps"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["Metal or wet sand"],
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "d56d5d48-56e5-4d3d-b6b7-ec1a9d7314e6",
            "topicId": "d56d5d48-56e5-4d3d-b6b7-ec1a9d7314e6",
            "question": "How long after all hot work is completed should the fire watch look for fires?",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "10 minutes",
                "30 minutes",
                "60 minutes",
                "4 hours"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["60 minutes"],
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "d56d5d48-56e5-4d3d-b6b7-ec1a9d7314e6",
            "topicId": "d56d5d48-56e5-4d3d-b6b7-ec1a9d7314e6",
            "question": "What is the meaning of the acronym OHS?",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "Overexposure heat symptoms",
                "Outlined health specifications",
                "Occupational health and safety",
                "Ordinance for hot work safety"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["Occupational health and safety"],
            "explanation": ""
        }
    ]
}
